HELEN PULCINI

CONTACT

Address: Guildford Surrey Phone: 07828 935848

Email: helenpulcini@gmail.com
Web: https://www.helenpulcini.c

om

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/helen-pulcini-b40587b7

EDUCATION

Digital Skills Bootcamp:
Software Development,
Expected in 02/2023
Just IT Training Ltd - London

GA Level 5 Diploma: Teaching English as a Foreign Language, 08/2021 **i-to-i TEFL** - Bournemouth

NVQ Level 2: Pharmacy education and skills, 11/2017 CIG Healthcare Partnership -London

Diploma of Higher Education: English, French, Spanish, 07/2002 Institute of Higher Education "F.Selmi" - Modena - Italy

HARD SKILLS

- Web Technology: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Operating System: Linux, Windows
- In Progress: MySQL, Python, React

PERSONAL PROFILE

After spending 7 years in retail environments in Italy and 6 years in different healthcare settings in the UK I am now ready for this new chapter in a completely different field.

Re-training and learning new skills as well as applying the ones I have acquired in my previous positions has been a rewarding journey so far and I am looking forward to continuing to learn.

My goal is to become fully proficient in the range of languages, tools and systems more in demand and keep up-to-date with what best practice in development looks like in order to bring strong and valuable skills to my future team.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Developer Trainee, 10/2022 to Current Just IT - London

- During the past 10 weeks of full immersion and intensive training I have acquired much more confidence in my ability to understand and apply concepts that I was unfamiliar with. I am currently studying Database and Python with the support of experienced tutors and gaining familiarity with the React library as a personal goal.
- So far I have been able to design and develop more than 10 projects in Html, Css and Javascript. The ones that I am most proud of are showcased in my portfolio. The time span within which all this has been achieved gives me the motivation to keep being committed to my ongoing learning and development with the aim of being able to deliver work to the highest possible standard.
- The course has given me a good foundation in producing clear, comprehensive, non-repetitive code. I aim to polish and optimise my projects as my knowledge of best practice and structure patterns improves. This is greatly enhancing my problem-solving skills since modifying existing code tends to produce unexpected outcomes which need to be rectified.
- Practising responsiveness is proving very useful to hone my designing skills. I try my best to design layouts that can be logically de-structured for smaller screens and I make sure to prefer relative units, which also helps meet accessibility standards.
- Being part of a cohort of like-minded students and actively sharing ideas, as well as struggles, has been very beneficial to enhance analytical and investigative skills while trying to help each other getting unstuck and at the same time researching and exploring new trends, technologies and practices.

SOFT SKILLS

- · Problem-Solving
- Meticulous Attention to Detail
- Solid Experience in Time Management and Prioritisation
- Organised and Deadline-Driven
- Dependable and Responsible
- Interpersonal Communication
- Collaborative Team Player
- Flexible and Adaptable
- Self-Motivated
- · Multi-tasking

HAPPY SKILLS

- Travelling and exploring.
- Reading books and watching movies in different languages.
- Singing at the top of my voice while driving.
- Attending live performances (music or art in general).
- More travelling.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Detailed work history and references available upon request.

Pharmacy Technician, 12/2016 to 10/2022 NHS / Private Healthcare - London, Bristol, Guildford - UK

Some of my duties:

Procurement related:

- Analyse patients treatments to procure specially manufactured medications in a timely manner.
- Oversee inventory identifying high-demand and out-of-stock items to achieve consistent supply levels.
- Collaborate with local GP practices and prescribers to optimise current stock availability and deal with medications shortages.
- Inform patients on potential supply and availability issues and recommending best course of action.

Patient related:

- Answer phone calls and address questions from customers and healthcare providers.
- Liaise with prescribers to verify medication dosages, repeat prescription authorisation, insurance provider and patient information.
- Maintain proper drug storage procedures, registries and records for controlled drugs.
- Assist with dispensing medications during busy periods to aid pharmacy workflow.
- Prepare intravenous solutions using aseptic techniques.

My skills:

- Procurement responsibilities have taught me how to organise my tasks around strict daily deadlines. I have also developed analytic skills to predict needs and possible obstacles in achieving set goals.
- Open communication and prompt information sharing with the multi-disciplinary team in dealing with drug shortages or supply disruptions has been a key element to minimise or completely avoid any adverse outcome for the patients.
- Constant interaction with patients, both in person or over the phone, has taught me empathy, respect, honesty and professionalism which I aim to apply in all my relations.
- The fast-paced environment of the dispensary and the pressure of patients waiting have equipped me with strong time management and organisation skills.
- Working in teams of different sizes, different abilities and different age ranges have shown me how important it is to prioritise duties according to the urgency and staffing situation, streamline procedures to allow everyone to comfortably perform to the best of their abilities and draw on the experience of senior members of staff for improvement.
- Dispensary duties which involved handling medications and patient sensitive information made me develop a quite sharp attention to details which is proving a very beneficial transferable skill while learning different programming languages and code syntax.

Sales Assistant, 07/2008 to 07/2015 Pollini Retail - Modena, Mantova, Parma - Italy

- I enhanced my flexibility and adaptability by carrying out both customer-facing and back-of-house duties.
- I have been in charge of receiving and processing new collection products and returns and maintaining a clear, easy-to-navigate stockroom.
- Resolving customer complaints and returns issues has been a
 very frequent challenge which I had to tackle with a
 proactive problem-solving approach, using insight and
 awareness of the customer's preferences and expected
 outcome.
- Other daily duties involved greeting customers and offering assistance with selecting merchandise, finding accessories and completing purchases, explaining information about quality, value and style of products to influence customer buying decisions, accepting and processing cash, cheque, card and mobile payments using POS systems.